<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.10.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-11-09T19:27:32-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Alec Whyte</title><subtitle>My name is Alec Whyte. I&apos;m an aspiring software developer. I studied Computer Science at the University of California, Irvine. I love coding, gaming, music, and  crafts. This is my personal portfolio site. Feel free to reach out to me via email or connect with me on LinkedIn!</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Whyte Weather</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/personal/projects/2025/11/04/whyte-weather.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Whyte Weather" /><published>2025-11-04T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2025-11-04T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/personal/projects/2025/11/04/whyte-weather</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/personal/projects/2025/11/04/whyte-weather.html"><![CDATA[<h3><a href="https://alec0915.pythonanywhere.com/">Check out my weather app here! </a></h3>
<p>This was my first proper project I did by myself outside of school. I usually struggle to find something I find interesting to work on, but this got me engaged to the point where I wanted to finish it. I worked on it off and on in my free time between work and d&amp;d. I’m still shocked that it both works and is just live on the internet now.</p>

<p>I had to learn how Flask worked to get this from a python script making API calls to a proper backend that feeds data to HTML files. I really like how Flask can not only create dynamic content on pages, but it can also create dynamic URLs for pages. It’s a cool idea to have template HTML files that act as a base structure that I fill with data depending on user input.</p>

<p>The python part was easy for me because it’s my most comfortable language. I did have to de-rust initially, but I got back into it pretty quick. I had forgotten all about function decorators by the time I started this project, so I’m glad I got a bit of a refresher with Flask’s primary decorator @app.route(). From my understanding, they give extra functionality to a function; in this case, it executes the function when the url is accessed. I think I’d like to play with decorators more to really get them down and understand them better.</p>

<p>HTML and CSS were not part of my curriculum at UCI, so I hadn’t really been exposed to either at all. They don’t seem too overly complex, but I don’t know all of the things I could do with them. I get the basic paragraph, header, font size, background color, etc., but I know there’s more to them both that I will explore as I go further.</p>

<p>I have it hosted on pythonanywhere because github pages doesn’t play nice with Flask.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="personal" /><category term="projects" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Check out my weather app here! This was my first proper project I did by myself outside of school. I usually struggle to find something I find interesting to work on, but this got me engaged to the point where I wanted to finish it. I worked on it off and on in my free time between work and d&amp;d. I’m still shocked that it both works and is just live on the internet now.]]></summary></entry></feed>